A Guide to the Minutes of the Virginia Board of Corrections, 1942-1980
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Minutes of the Virginia Board of Corrections, 1942-1980
The Library of Virginia
32260
10 cu. ft. (10 boxes)
Virginia. Board of Corrections.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
These records are open for research but it may be necessary for an archivist to review the files before they can be used by patrons for research purposes or before any copies of the records can be made. Privacy protected and other protected information is considered confidential and restricted from public access for 75 years per Code of Virginia 42.1-78. Types of materials restricted include: social security numbers.
Acquisition Information
Transferred on 27 November 1984 by the Dept. of Corrections, 4615 W. Broad St., Richmond, Virginia, 23261.
Historical Information
The Department of Corrections is administered by a director who is appointed by the governor and subject to legislative confirmation. The State Board of Corrections consists of nine members appointed by the governor for four-year terms. The mission of the department is to "Protect the people from a crime by assisting communities in preventing juvenile delinquency, controlling persons sentenced by the courts, and offering programs to help offenders lead crime-free lives after release."
There are three major divisions: Administration, Institutions, which has regional court service units, and Community Corrections, which has regional probation and parole services.
The Virginia Board of Corrections was renamed the Virginia Board of Local and Regional Jails in 2020 (SB 622, Chap. 759, approved April 6, 2020).
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Minutes, Index, 1948-1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Minutes, Index, 1956-1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Minutes, Index, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Minutes, 1942 July-December (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Minutes, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Minutes, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Minutes, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Minutes, 1951 January-June (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Minutes, 1951 July-December (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Minutes, 1952 January-June (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Minutes, 1952 July-December (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Minutes, 1953 January-June (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Minutes, 1953 July-December (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Minutes, 1954 January-June (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Minutes, 1954 July-December (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Minutes, 1955 January-June (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Minutes, 1955 July-December (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Minutes, 1956 January-June (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Minutes, 1956 July-December (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Minutes, 1957 January-June (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Minutes, 1957 July-December (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Minutes, 1958 January-June (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Minutes, 1958 July-November (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Minutes, 1958 November-December (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Minutes, 1959 January-May (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Minutes, 1959 June-September (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Minutes, 1959 October-December (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Minutes, 1960 January-April (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Minutes, 1960 April-July (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Minutes, 1960 August-December (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Minutes, 1961 January-June (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Minutes, 1961 July-December (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Minutes, 1962 January-June (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Minutes, 1962 July-December (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Minutes, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Minutes, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Minutes, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Minutes, 1966 January-June (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Minutes, 1966 July-December (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Minutes, 1967 January-June (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Minutes, 1967 July-December (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Minutes, 1968 January-June (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Minutes, 1968 July-December (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Minutes, 1969 January-June (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Minutes, 1969 July-December (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Minutes, 1969 October-1970 February (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Minutes, 1970 March-July (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Minutes, 1970 August-December (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Minutes, 1970 January-June (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Minutes, 1970 July-December (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Minutes, 1971 January-June (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Minutes, 1971 July-August (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Minutes, 1971 August-December (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Minutes, 1971 January-April (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Minutes, 1971 May-December (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Minutes, 1972 January-June (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Minutes, 1972 July-December (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Minutes, 1972 January-December (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Minutes, 1973 January-June (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Minutes, 1973 June-July (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Minutes, 1973 August-September (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Minutes, 1973 September-October (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Minutes, 1973 November-December (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Minutes, 1973 January-December (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Minutes, 1974 January-February (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Minutes, 1974 February-March (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Minutes, 1974 April (Appendix 5) (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1974 July 12 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1974 August 7-8 (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1974 September 11-12 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1974 October 9-10 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1974 November 13-14 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1974 December (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Minutes, 1974 January-December (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Minutes, 1975 January-December (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1975 January 9 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1975 February 13 (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
- Minutes, 1975 March (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1975 March 12 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1975 April 18 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Minutes, 1975 May (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1975 May 8 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1975 June 11-12 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1975 July 9-10 (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1975 August 12-13 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1975 September 9-10 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1975 October 16 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1975 November 18-19 (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1975 December 9-10 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Minutes, 1976 January-June (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1976 January 13-14 (Box 5, Folder 2-6)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1976 August 10-11 (Box 5, Folder 7-9)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1976 September 13-14 (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1976 October 12 (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1976 November 9-10 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1976 December 14-15 (Box 6, Folder 3-6)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1977 January 11-12 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1977 February 9 (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1977 March 8-9 (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1977 April 12-13 (Box 6, Folder 13-14)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1977 May 10-11 (Box 6, Folder 15-17)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1977 June 14-15 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1977 July 12-13 (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
- Minutes, Special Meeting, 1977 July 22 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Minutes, 1977 July-December (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1977 August 9-10 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1977 September 13-14 (Box 7, Folder 9-10)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1977 October 11-12 (Box 7, Folder 11-12)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1977 November 9 (Box 7, Folder 13-14)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1977 December 13-14 (Box 7, Folder 15-17)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1978 January 10-11 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Minutes, 1978 January-April (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1978 February 14-15 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1978 March 14-15 (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1978 April 11-12 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1978 May 9-10 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1978 June 13-14 (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1978 July 12-13 (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1978 August 8-9 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1978 September 12-13 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1978 October 10-11 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1978 November 14-15 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1978 December 13 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1979 January 10 (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1979 February 14 (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1979 March 14 (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1979 April 10-11 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1979 May 8-9 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1979 June 19-20 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1979 July 11 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1979 August 14-15 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1979 September 11-12 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1979 October 9-10 (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1979 November 13-14 (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1979 December 11-12 (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1980 January 9 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1980 February 12-13 (Box 10, Folder 2-3)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1980 March 11-12 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1980 April 9 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1980 May 13-14 (Box 10, Folder 6-7)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1980 June 10-11 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1980 July 16 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1980 August 12-13 (Box 10, Folder 10-12)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1980 September 9-10 (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1980 October 14-15 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1980 November 11-12 (Box 10, Folder 16-19)
- Minutes, Meeting, 1980 December 9-10 (Box 10, Folder 20)